we're going to
write a program that prompts the user to
input a number between 0 and 100.
the program will then display a message
to the user reporting whether the number
is between
0 and 50 51 and 100
or above 100 so the first step here is
simply to prompt the user for a number
so we'll use put s to output a message
to the user
please enter a number between 0 and 100.
we want to capture that user input and
store it in a variable
let's call that variable number
and in order to pause program execution
and wait for the user to give their
input
we'll use the get s method
and we'll chain a method call to chomp
on the get s method
and this will remove the newline
character from user input
so i'm going to run our program as it is
now and use the p
method to output number after we've
captured it from the user
so i'll run our program i'm prompted for
a number
i'll enter 50. now you'll notice that on
the last line there
when our program output number it output
a string
remember that all user input comes in as
but because we're going to want to
compare this number
to integers between 0 and 100
we want number to be an integer
we can store the user input as an
integer in our variable number
by chaining a method called 2i
i'm going to run our program the same
way one more time
[Music]
again i'll enter 50 and this time when
we use
p to output that number back to us
you can see that it's an integer
so now that we've stored the user input
as an integer
in the variable number we can compare
number
to different integers in order to
display the appropriate message to the
user
we can do this using an if statement
so first we want to make sure the user
didn't enter a negative number
so the condition we'll provide to our if
statement is
if number is less than zero if this
comparison returns true
we'll output you can't enter a negative
number
if this next branch of our if statement
is being evaluated
then we know that the number must be
greater than or equal to zero
so now we simply need to check whether
the number is less than or equal to 50.
if this condition evaluates as true
then we know that number is between 0
and 50.
we'll output a message to the user
reflecting that and we can use string
interpolation
to display the number
on line 8 we'll write a condition to
determine whether number is between
51 and 100. again if we've reached this
branch of our
if statement we already know that the
number is greater than 50.
so we simply need to check whether it's
less than or equal to 100
if the number is less than or equal to
we'll output a similar message
lastly we'll give our if statement in
else clause
and the code in this branch of our if
statement will be executed
if none of the other conditions in our
if statement evaluated as true
and in this case that means the number
the user provided
is over 100
so we'll display a message reflecting
that
and now let's run our code
so first we'll input a negative number
and we see the appropriate message
let's enter a number between 0 and 50.
i'll enter
15.
this time i'll choose a number between
51 and 100.
and lastly i'm going to choose a number
over 100
and we see the appropriate message
you